

DAMJAN KOLEVSKI damjan.kolevski@gmail.com damjankol.github.io/portfolio

Product Design Engineer based in Prague

with a bachelor's degree of Industrial Design in Mechanical Engineering, and five years of work experience in that field, followed by an academy of UX Design, and four years of work experience on that position.

His strongest competences are: Research, Prototyping, Programming, New product development, Graphic Design, CAD, Mechanical Engineering, Project management.

Industries he experiences: IT, Healthcare, Smart Manufacturing, Sport, Hospitality.

Personally, he is described as: committed, honest, reliable, enthusiastic, creative, details-oriented, communicative, adaptable, patient, tolerant.

DIGITAL COMPETENCE

- Figma, Adobe XD, Miro (Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototypes)
- HTML, CSS, JS, Angular, SQL (Programming)
- Photoshop, Illustrator (Graphic Design)
- InVision, 3ds MAX (Animation)
- Google Looker Studio (Data visualization)
- Azure DevOps, GitLab (Agile developing)
- Solidworks, AutoCAD (3D assembly modelling, 2D tech. drawing)
- ProCast, Matlab, Adams (Dynamic simulations)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Product Designer

ALLPLAN, Industry: IT, SaaS, Construction Apr. 2024 - present, Prague

- UX design based on the design system (Figma)
- Writing Requirements for development (Azure DevOps)
- Testing developed requirements and writing Test Cases
- Writing help documentation for the developed features
- Providing 2nd line support for users' inquiries
- Fixing bugs in the scope of the configurable UI

UX & Frontend Developer

OG Soft, Industry: IT, Mobile App Mar. 2023 - Mar. 2024. Usti nad Orlici

- UI Design (following Material 3 design system)
- Frontend programming (in Angular)
- Working in Agile environment (with GitLab)

UX Designer

TRIGAMA INT., Industry: IT, Mobile App, Wellness Jan. 2022 – Dec. 2022, Prague

- User Flows, User Interfaces (prototyping with Figma)
- User Interviews, User Tests (with Loop11)
- Working in Agile environment (with Azure DevOps)

UX Design Engineer

ATS GLOBAL, Industry: IT, SaaS, Industry 4.0 Apr. 2021 - Feb. 2022, Skopje

- User Researching, User Tests (with Userlytics)
- Mapping User Flows (with Miro)
- Designing Wireframes (with InVision)
- Designing Prototypes (with Figma)
- Implementing Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)
- Planning a development of Design System
- Working in Agile environment (with Azure DevOps)

Mechanical Engineer

several companies Mar. 2015 - Sep. 2020, Skopje, Granada

Graphic Designer & Events Organizer

Macedonian Canoe Federation, Industry: Sport Mar. 2014 - present (part-time), Skopje

EDUCATION

BRAINSTER Academy of UX/UI Design

Jul. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Pre-program/Graphic Design (Photoshop, Illustrator)
- Fundamentals of UX/UI Design
- Tools: AdobeXD, Figma, InVision (Information Architecture, Wireframes, Prototypes)
- Design Systems, Responsive Design
- Front End Programming (HTML, CSS, JS)
- Storytelling, Pitching

MOTIVA Management Training

Feb. 2013 - Mar. 2013

Communication Skills; Developing and Managing Effective Teams; Entrepreneurship, Developing SMEs, Writing Business Plan; Financial Mgmt.; Leadership and Business Negotiation; Strategic Mgmt. and Business Ethics; Export Marketing; Presentation Skills; Change Mgmt.; Human Resources Mgmt.; Quality Mgmt.

University Ss. Cyril & Methodius in Skopje, Bachelor of Mech. Engineering in Industrial Design

Sep. 2011 - Jan. 2015

- Mechanical Engineering,
- New Product Development.
- 3D assembly modelling & 2D technical drawing (Solidworks, AutoCAD, MAYA, CATIA),
- Geometric Dimensioning and Tolerancing, Design for Manufacturability, Material Properties
- Graphic Design (Photoshop),
- Dynamic Simulation (Matlab, Adams),
- Animation (3ds MAX).
- Web Design/HTML/CSS (Dreamweaver)

Vocational Courses

- IBM: Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner (August 2021)
- IDF: User Research Methods and Best Practices (July 2021)
- IDF: Conducting Usability Testing (June 2021)

PERSONAL INFORMATION

- age: Millennial
- languages: English (fluent), Czech (beginner), Spanish (intermed.), French (beginner), Macedonian (native), Bulgarian (fluent), Croatian (fluent), Serbian (fluent).
- driver's license: B category (active driver)
- hobbies: Painting, Photography, Architecture, Folklore, Ecology, Humanitarian Volunteering, Tennis, Skiing, Volleyball, Hiking, White-water kayaking, Karate, Scouting, Dancing, Ice-skating, Table-tennis, Billiard, Ultimate Frisbee, Playing Piano, Flute...